ALEXIS QUINTUÑA

alexisiquintuna@gmail.com I (646) 730-3569

linkedin.com/in/alexis-quintuna | github.com/alexisquintuna | alexisquintuna.com

Bilingual C# Full-Stack Software Developer, using passion and determination to break down complex problems and finding simple solutions with a line of code at a time. Client-focused and web development experience with strong communication skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- → Object-Oriented Programming: C#/.Net | JavaScript
- → Web Application Development: HTML | CSS | ASP.NET Core | Web API | Vue.js | React | Node.js | Express | TailWind
- → Database Programming: ADO.NET | Table Design | E/R diagrams | SQL Server | REST | MVC | MongoDB
- → Development Tool & Techniques: Agile | Unit Testing | Integration Testing | Unix Command Line Navigation | Git | Visual Studio | Visual Studio Code | Figma
- → Additional Skills: English(Native), Spanish (Native)

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

- **Tenmo App** Designed and implemented JWT authorization and authentication to build an application that allows one to login into their account and securely transfer money from one account to another in a 2-person team using C# in a capstone project. Users are able to manage their accounts through a console menu that uses RestSharp to access an API, which would then update their accounts in an SQL database.
- Candy Store Cash Register Built a cash register application to keep track of inventory, sales, and money received or returned. The application was created by enforcing coding standards and best practices with the help of my pair programming partner.
- Genere Natus 2.0 Created and designed with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React as the library. I developed a landing page web app for a car club I created. Initially, what <u>started</u> as vanilla HTML and CSS, With tools I taught myself I went back and designed a new version of the site in Figma to then develop it using React to test my front-end abilities and the tools I self-taught myself.

EDUCATION

Tech Elevator, Columbus, OH

SEPT 2022 - PRESENT

Currently attending a 14-week full-stack coding boot camp learning how to create dynamic web-based software systems using .NET/C# providing 800+ hours of development education and application.

Udemy JAN 2022 - AUG 2022

React - The Complete Guide

The Complete 2022 Web Development Bootcamp

SUNY Farmingdale, Farmingdale, NY

AUG 2017 - MAY 2018

30 credits toward a Bachelors of Science Degree

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Roosevelt Coffeehouse, Columbus, OH

SEPT 2019 - PRESENT

Lead Barista

- Juggled different projects, roles, and event planning with relative ease.
- Ability to work under pressure in a fast-paced environment amid distractions and interruptions.
- Appointed and took the initiative to handle a coffee shop location by myself and handle over 100 transactions a day.
- Took ownership of accomplishing new and different requests to enhance the shop's reputation and generate revenues.

OfRoot, Columbus, OH MAR 2021 – AUG 2021

Intern Web Developer

- Designed, built, and maintained websites, using authoring or scripting languages.
- Documented test plans, testing procedures, and test results.